newschool.edu 2019-12-06

# Privacy Policy | The New School

Revision 1.3, October 1, 2019

The New School recognizes the importance of protecting the privacy and security of your personal information. We provide this Privacy Statement to help you understand what we may do with any personal information that we obtain from you. By providing your personal information to us, you signify your acceptance of this Privacy Statement, and agree that we may collect, use, and disclose your personal information as described herein. If you do not agree to this statement, please do not provide your personal information to us via this website.

## Information You Provide to Us

To communicate effectively with visitors to our website, we may ask you for personally-identifiable information that can include, by way of illustration, your name, mailing address, email address, telephone number, or graduation date. It is your choice to provide us with this personal information; we will only collect personal information that you provide. The New School will never sell or trade personally-identifiable information you provide to us through this website to other colleges, universities, organizations, or businesses unless we have your consent to share the information, or we are sharing such information in response to a subpoena, court order, or other legal process.

#### Continuing Education Registration

If you use our website to register for Adult or Continuing Education classes (including those offered through Schools of Public Engagement, Parsons School of Design, Parsons Summer Programs, and Mannes School of Music Extension Program), we require that you provide us with certain personally-identifiable information including your name, address, telephone number, email address, Student ID number, date of birth, and credit card number. To meet Internal Revenue Service requirements, we also ask, but do not require, that you provide your Social Security number. This information is necessary to process your application and to contact you. When you submit this information via the registration form, it is encrypted using Secure Socket Layer/Transport Layer Security (SSL/TLS) encryption when transmitting it to our website.

## Information Gathered Automatically

When you visit our site, some information such as your Internet network address, Internet service provider, operating system, web browser version, site from which you arrived, and the time and date of your visit may be collected automatically as part of normal site operation. This information is not personally identifiable, and we do not link this information to any personally identifiable information you submit while using our site. This information is used solely to track web browsing patterns to better understand how our site is being used, and when necessary, to troubleshoot problems with the site.

#### Cookies

A cookie is a small text file that is stored on your computer for record-keeping purposes. Session cookies expire and are removed from your hard drive when you close your web browser. Persistent cookies remain on your hard drive for extended periods of time. We use both session and persistent cookies on this site. The use of cookies helps us to assist your use of certain aspects of the site, and also helps us evaluate usage patterns so that we can improve site content and organization. We do not link the information we store in persistent cookies to any personally-identifiable information you submit while using our site.   
You can delete persistent cookies by following the directions provided with your web browser. You may also set your web browser to reject cookies from our site. If you choose to do this, you may still use our site, but you may not be able to access the full functionality of some sections of the site. You can obtain more information about how to manage cookies from [aboutcookies.org](http://www.aboutcookies.org/).

#### Clear GIFs

We employ a software technology called “clear GIFs” (also called “web beacons” or “web bugs”) to help us better manage content on our site by informing us about which content is effective. Clear GIFs are tiny graphics with a unique identifier, similar in function to cookies, and are used to track the online movements of website visitors. In contrast to cookies, which are stored on your computer’s hard drive, clear GIFs are embedded invisibly on web pages and are about the size of the period at the end of this sentence. We do not link the information gathered by clear GIFs to any personally-identifiable information you submit while using our site.   
We also use clear GIFs in our HTML-based emails to let us know which emails have been opened by recipients. This allows us to gauge the effectiveness of certain communications and the effectiveness of our marketing campaigns. If you would like to opt out of these emails, follow the directions at the bottom of the email message.

#### Google Analytics

Some sections of our website use Google Analytics, a web analytics service provided by Google, Inc. Google Analytics uses cookies to help us analyze how people use our site. The information generated by the cookie about your use of the website includes your Internet network address. This information will be transmitted to and stored by Google on its servers. Google will use this information for the purpose of evaluating your use of the website, compiling reports on website activity for our website administrators, and providing other services relating to website activity and Internet usage. Google may also transfer this information to third parties where required to do so by law, or where such third parties process the information on Google’s behalf. Google will not associate your network address with any other data held by Google. To disable Google Analytics’ tracking of your usage of our site, you may disable cookies in your browser; however, please note that by doing so you may not be able to use the full functionality of this website. By using this website, you consent to the processing of data about you by Google in the manner and for the purposes set out above. To learn more, visit the [Google Analytics Privacy Overview](http://www.google.com/intl/en/analytics/privacyoverview.html) and [Google’s privacy policy](http://www.google.com/intl/en/policies/privacy/).

## Co-branded Sites

The New School works with a variety of business partners to collect and manage information from prospective students and employees and to provide services to students, staff, and alumni. As part of the services they provide, these companies operate websites on behalf of The New School and may display The New School’s name, logos, and other information to identify themselves as New School–affiliated websites. These sites, because they are not owned or controlled by The New School, are not governed by this Privacy Statement.   
We have provided links below to the privacy statements of many of the business partners with whom we work to collect information and provide services. If you have questions about a company not listed below, please see the “Contact Us” section at the bottom of this webpage.

  * This is the privacy statement for _Hobsons ApplyYourself_ , which we use to collect undergraduate and graduate applications, collect information requests from prospective students, and schedule campus visits: 
  * This is the privacy statement for the _Common App_ , which is used by undergraduate students to apply to Eugene Lang College of Liberal Arts: 
  * This is the privacy statement for _World Education Services_ , which we use to evaluate academic credits earned at institutions outside the United States: 
  * This is the privacy statement for _TouchNet_ , which we use to process application fees and tuition, residence hall, and meal plan payments by Automated Clearing House or credit card transactions (except for Continuing Education): 
  * This is the privacy statement for _PeopleAdmin_ , which we use to collect résumés and employment applications from prospective employees: 
  * This is the privacy statement for _Google Apps for Education_ , which we use to provide electronic mail and other collaboration services to faculty, staff, students, and alumni: 
  * Google also provides a description of some of the privacy features specific to the _Google Apps for Education_ version of their services: 
  * This is the privacy statement for the _Canvas_ _Learning Management System_ , which we use to deliver the online components of most courses at The New School: 
  * This is the privacy statement for _Edublogs_ , which we use to provide the New School Learning Portfolio: 
  * This is the privacy statement for Starfish CONNECT, Starfish EARLY ALERT, and Starfish ADVISING applications (Student Success Network), which we use to help improve communications between students and advisors and to connect students with New School resources: 
  * This is the privacy statement for Workday (MyDay), which we use to provide human resources services such as payroll, benefits administration, time off and leave management, etc., to employees: 
  * This is the privacy statement for _Listrak_ , which we use to manage some of our email marketing campaigns: 

## Links to Other Sites

This website contains links to other sites that are not owned or controlled by The New School. Please be aware that The New School is not responsible for the privacy practices of such other sites.   
We encourage you to be aware when you leave our site and to read the privacy statements of each and every website to which you provide personally-identifiable information.   
This Privacy Statement applies only to information collected by this website.

## Use of This Site by Children

The New School offers programs for children at certain times of the year, and provides information about those programs on this site. However, this site is not designed for or intended for use by children under the age of 13, and we request that such individuals do not submit personally-identifiable information to this site.

## Security

We follow generally accepted industry practices to protect the personal information submitted to us, both during transmission and once we receive it. No method of transmission over the Internet, or method of electronic storage, is 100% secure, however. Therefore, while we strive to use commercially reasonable means to protect your personal information, we cannot guarantee its absolute security. 

## Changes to This Privacy Statement

We reserve the right to modify this privacy statement at any time, so please review it frequently. If we make material changes to this privacy statement, we will update the revision number and date at the top of this webpage and describe the changes below.

### Revision History

Revision

| 

Date

| 

Description of Change  
  
---|---|---  
  
1.0

| 

Oct. 19, 2012

| 

Initial publication  
  
1.1

| 

Nov. 14, 2014

| 

Added “date of birth” under “Continuing Education Registration” and clarified language about collecting Social Security numbers

Added “application fees” under TouchNet usage description

Updated links to privacy statements: _Hobsons ApplyYourself, Common App, PeopleAdmin_

Deleted co-branded sites we no longer use: _Embark, Unified Application for Music and Performing Arts_

Added new co-branded sites: _Canvas, Edublogs, NACElink Career Services Manager_  
  
1.2

| 

May 4, 2017

| 

Updated links to privacy statements: Common App, PeaoplAdmin, Canvas, Edublogs

Updated the list of Starfish applications to include EARLY ALERT and ADVISING

Deleted co-branded sites we no longer use: NACElink

Added new co-branded sites: The Village
